Fahadh Faasil

Full-stack web developer with over 9 years of experience analyzing, designing, developing, and integrating front-end & back-end-based applications, Possesses knowledge of web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AngularJS, Ajax, and PHP. Key achievement: created a web application that allowed 75K users to search for nearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer

November 2015 – Present

Resume Worded, New York, NY

- Created a web application that allowed 75K users to search fornearby restaurants based on their location with 89% accuracy.
- Worked with a team of 27 developers that created an ecommercewebsite using PHP, MySQL, and JavaScript within 3 months.
- Developed a responsive email template in HTML5 and CSS3 that increased the clickthrough rate by 78%, an improvement from previous years.
- Participated in code reviews of 300 developers' ensuring that all code complied 100% with coding standards & best practices.

Front End Developer

February 2013 – October 2015

Growthsi, San Francisco, CA

- Developed front-end code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery to create a responsive web application that works across 29 devices, including desktops and tablets.
- Optimized 29 web pages for speed and performance by eliminatingunnecessary scripts/styles and increasing load time by 69%.
- Created an interactive map for a real estate company's website that allowed 7K users to search by neighborhood and get real-time feedback about a property.
- Partnered with 28 UX designers on redesigning Growthsi existing site; improving conversion rate by 77%.

Software Engineer

June 2010 – January 2013

Resume Worded's Exciting Company, New York, NY

- Designed and launched an automated testing framework using Python's unittest module, which reduced manual QA time from 9weeks to 10 hours per release.
- Slashed development costs by creating reusable components such as database wrappers, and authentication modules, resulting in \$1M annual savings for RWEC.
- Initiated a new feature in the RWEC's flagship product that allowed customers to purchase multiple licenses simultaneously, increasingannual revenue by 88%.
- Created a web application that allows 2.7K users to create and manage their online accounts for the products of RWEC, reducing customer support calls by 79%.

CONTACT

- Minneapolis, MN (Open to Remote)
- · +1-234-456-789
- email@resumeworded.com
- · linkedin.com/in/username
- · github.com/resumeworded

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Bootstrap (Advanced)
- WordPress (Experienced)
- · Web Design
- · ASP.NET MVC
- · ASP.NET

Industry Knowledge:

- · Amazon Web Services
- Front-end Development
- Web Applications

Tools and Software:

- Docker
- jQuery
- Linux
- Apache
- Nginx
- Don't forget to use

ResumeWorded to scan

your resume

before you send it off (it's free andproven to get you more jobs)

EDUCATION

Resume Worded University Bachelor of Science Computer Science Boston, MA — May 2018

Awards: Resume Worded Teaching Fellow (only 5 awarded to class), Dean's List 2012 (Top 10%)

OTHER

- Certified in Java SE 8Programmer.
- · Certified Web Developer.
- · Oracle Certified Associate.